What's going on here?
這裡發生了什麼事？
This is the labyrinth ARIBISU.
這就是迷宮ARIBISU。
There's a Gate of Destruction somewhere in here.
這裡某處有破壞之門。
Staying here won't solve anything.
留在這裡解決不了任何問題。
Let's go ahead.
讓我們繼續。
what is this?
這是什麼？
KOYORI.
KOYORI。
SOUMA, RYUGA.
SOUMA、RYUGA。
let's go.
我們走吧。
SOUMA.
SOUMA。
RYUGA, what's wrong?
RYUGA，怎麼了？
what is this?
這是什麼？
The layout of the walls here is different from when I passed by earlier.
這裡的牆壁佈局和我之前經過的時候不一樣。
I think the walls are moving and the path is changing.
我認為牆壁正在移動，路徑正在改變。
Original work by KEITA AMEMIYA.
雨宮惠太的原創作品。
Produced by TOHOKUSHINSHA.
東北新社製作。
Executive producer, KIYOTAKA NINOMIYA.
執行製片人，二宮清隆。
GARO：Heir To Steel Armor.
GARO：Heir To Steel Armor。
WATARU KURIYAMA.
栗山涉。
ON NAKANO.
在中野。
MIKO NAKAZAWA.
中澤美子。
TOMOKA KUROTANI.
黑谷智香。
MASATO HAGIWARA.
萩原正人。
HIRONOBU KAGEYAMA.
影山博宣。
KENTETSU ASAKA, AKIHIRO YAMAMOTO, SHUN NISHIME.
淺坂健哲、山本昭宏、西目俊。
Planning producer, Tanaka Aya. Producer, Higa Ichiro, SHUHEI OKABAYASHI.
企劃製作人Tanaka Aya。製作人：Higa Ichiro、岡林修平。
Screenplay, RIUJI YOSHIZAKI. Screenplay cooperation: YOSHIKATSU KIMURA.
劇本：吉崎理二。劇本合作：木村芳勝。
Stunt director, MASAKI SUZUMURA.
特技導演鈴村正樹。
Director, YASUHIRO MATSUDA.
導演：松田康弘。
flash.
閃光。
RYUGA.
RYUGA。
What did you think after cutting HORROR yesterday?
昨天剪完HORROR後有什麼感想？
There were times when my father would make the same face as you after he killed a HORROR.
有時候，父親拍完HORROR後，也會做出跟你一樣的表情。
It's an expression that seems to be mourning the HORROR that was killed.
那個表情似乎是在哀悼被殺的HORROR。
I thought that the Makai Knight should be strong.
我覺得Makai Knight應該很強。
There's something I'm missing.
我缺少一些東西。
Let me tell you GODOU's words.
讓我告訴你GODOU的話。
You are KOUZAN KNIGHT ZANGO.
你是KOUZAN KNIGHT ZANGO。
GODOU.
GODOU。
A customer is waiting for you.
一位顧客正在等你。
who are you?
你是誰？
I am Ryuuga Dogai.
我是龍牙道貝。
Are you a Golden Knight?
你是金騎士嗎？
I'm GODOU.
我是GODOU。
nice to meet you.
很高興見到你。
By the way, why is the Golden Knight here?
對了，金騎士怎麼會在這裡？
I came here to retrain myself.
我來這裡是為了重新鍛鍊自己。
Have you ever wanted to become stronger?
你有沒有想過要變得更強？
The Golden Knight is still on the road to finding strength.
金騎士仍在尋找力量的路上。
What special move did you use to kill HORROR?
你用了什麼必殺技來殺死HORROR？
That technique is the SENKOUKENBU.
那技法就是SENKOUKENBU。
Please teach me the SENKOUKENBU.
請教我SENKOUKENBU。
That special move is not something that can be taught easily.
那絕招可不是輕易就能學會的。
The secret of SENKOUKENBU is to use the darkness to acquire a stronger light.
SENKOUKENBU的秘密是利用黑暗獲得更強的光明。
SENKOUKENBU is a sword of light.
SENKOUKENBU是一把光之劍。
If you don't have the heart to overcome the darkness, you will be eroded by the darkness and lose your sense of self.
如果你沒有戰勝黑暗的心，你就會被黑暗侵蝕，失去自我意識。
I will overcome the darkness, I have overcome the trials of darkness.
我會戰勝黑暗，我已經戰勝了黑暗的考驗。
If you have conquered the darkness, you will be able to learn the SENKOUKENBU.
如果你征服了黑暗，你就能學會SENKOUKENBU。
GODOU, please teach me that special move.
GODOU，請教我那個必殺技吧。
I understand, you can follow me.
我明白了，你可以關注我。
what is this?
這是什麼？
I traveled all over the place to solve the mystery of the Gate of Destruction.
為了解開破壞之門的謎團，我走遍了各地。
This is one of the pieces I got there.
這是我在那裡得到的作品之一。
The first step in SENKOUKENBU is to connect with SOUL METAL through heart-to-heart communication.
SENKOUKENBU的第一步是透過心與心的溝通與SOUL METAL建立連結。
Please control the evil spirit that resides in the sword.
請控制住劍中的邪氣。
RYUGA, please turn darkness into light.
RYUGA，請把黑暗變成光。
This is exactly what I thought.
這正是我的想法。
you have the talent.
你有才華。
RYUGA, please concentrate your mind and put your feelings into the light.
RYUGA，請集中你的注意力，將你的感受傾注在光明中。
let's start.
開始吧。
RYUGA, you are amazing.
RYUGA，你太棒了。
It's a great SENKOUKENBU.
這是一場很棒的SENKOUKENBU。
My armor suddenly disappeared.
我的鎧甲突然消失了。
SENKOUKENBU involves heavy damage to the mind and body.
SENKOUKENBU對身心都會造成嚴重傷害。
Loaded armor will be forced back to avoid damage.
裝載的裝甲將被迫向後以避免損壞。
Everyone starts out like you.
每個人都像你一樣開始。
You'll get used to it eventually.
你最終會習慣的。
RYUGA.
RYUGA。
SENKOUKENBU has a pair of special moves.
SENKOUKENBU有一對必殺技。
It turns light into jet-black darkness, and its special move is a sword of darkness that covers that darkness.
將光化為漆黑的黑暗，必殺技是覆蓋黑暗的黑暗之劍。
Do those who use its skills wear darkness?
使用其技能的人是否穿著黑暗？
The name of his special move is SENEIKENBU.
他的必殺技的名字是“SENEIKENBU”。
SENEIKENBU.
SENEIKENBU。
SENKOUKENBU and SENEIKENBU are closely connected.
SENKOUKENBU和SENEIKENBU是緊密相連的。
Since you have overcome the trials of darkness, you will definitely be able to master SENEIKENBU someday.
既然你已經克服了黑暗的考驗，總有一天你一定能成為SENEIKENBU的大師。
You keep training and don't slack off.
你要堅持訓練，不要鬆懈。
I understand.
我明白。
I taught the Golden Knight the SENKOUKENBU before my son.
我在兒子麵前教過金騎士SENKOUKENBU。
do you have a son?
你有兒子嗎？
My son is competitive and it's hard for me.
我兒子很有競爭力，這對我來說很難。
It's hard to take care of my son.
照顧我的兒子很困難。
I don't seem to think you're having a hard time.
我似乎不認為你過得很艱難。
Does it seem like that to you?
你覺得是這樣嗎？
I guess every father is like that.
我想每個父親都是這樣。
I understand.
我明白。
RYUGA.
RYUGA。
For me, my son and GARO are the same.
對我來說，我的兒子和GARO是一樣的。
It means hope, right?
這意味著希望，對嗎？
That's hope.
這就是希望。
My son is my hope.
我的兒子是我的希望。
Thank you for teaching me special techniques.
謝謝你教我特殊的技巧。
Please use SENKOUKENBU after assessing the battle situation.
請在評估戰況後使用SENKOUKENBU。
I will train and master the SENKOUKENBU.
我會訓練並掌握SENKOUKENBU。
I'm encouraged by you.
我受到你的鼓勵。
I will teach my son SENKOUKENBU someday.
有一天我會教我的兒子SENKOUKENBU。
Your son will become a fine Makai Realm Knight like you.
你的兒子將會成為像你一樣優秀的Makai Realm騎士。
RYUGA.
RYUGA。
When you meet my son, I will entrust him to you.
當你見到我的兒子時，我會將他託付給你。
GODOU was planning to teach you the SENKOUKENBU.
GODOU本來打算教你SENKOUKENBU。
GODOU was thinking.
GODOU思考著。
GODOU was hesitant about teaching you techniques.
GODOU對於是否要教你技巧猶豫不決。
It was no surprise that he was hesitant about teaching me special moves.
毫不奇怪，他對教我特殊動作猶豫不決。
SOUMA.
SOUMA。
Keep your willpower strong.
保持堅強的意志力。
SOUMA, please return your consciousness to normal.
SOUMA，請讓你的意識恢復正常。
I'm a failure.
我是個失敗者。
All phenomena exist at the origin.
一切現像都存在於本源。
GODOU taught me these words, saying, ``Please remember these words when you are lost.''
GODOU教導我這些話時說道：“當你迷路時，請記住這些話。”
How about thinking back to when you decided to become a knight?
回想一下你決定成為騎士的時候怎麼樣？
You may find what you are missing.
你可能會找到你所缺少的東西。
origin.
起源。
SOUMA.
SOUMA。
KOYORI.
KOYORI。
How do you know this place?
你怎麼知道這個地方的？
This is all thanks to MUTSUGI.
這都是MUTSUGI的功勞。
Everyone please hurry.
請大家快點。
wait a minute.
等一下。
KOYORI.
KOYORI。
What are the words carved on the stone monument?
石碑上刻著什麼字？
A person with light desires blood, not the end.
有光明的人渴望的是血，而不是結局。
All phenomena have their origin.
一切現像都有其根源。
I now know how to get to the Gate of Destruction.
我現在知道如何到達破壞之門了。
The words "without seeking an end" written on the stone monument may refer to the place of the beginning.
石碑上寫的「不求終結」四個字，或許就是指起點的地方。
"It wants blood."
“它想要血。”
This is the answer.
這就是答案。
what is this?
這是什麼？
This is the entrance to the Gate of Destruction.
這是破壞之門的入口。
let's go.
我們走吧。
be careful!
當心！
KOYORI.
KOYORI。
Let's go ahead.
讓我們繼續。
MUTSUGI.
MUTSUGI。
SOUMA.
SOUMA。
Don't forget what you came here for.
別忘了你來這裡的目的。
That is the Gate of Destruction.
那是破壞之門。
No way.
決不。
That's true?
這是真的？
That's my father.
那是我的父親。
No way.
決不。
DOUGAI RYUGA, WATARU KURIYAMA.
道DOUGAIRYUGA、栗山涉。
SHIRAHANE SOUMA, ON NAKANO. KOYORI, MIKO NAKAZAWA.
SHIRAHANESOUMA，ON NAKANO。KOYORI、中澤美子。
KOUZAN KNIGHT ZANGO, YUGO FUJII. JIGARUSU, KOHEI MATSUOKA. IRUBUA, YUKA SUZUMURA.
高山騎士藏吾、藤井佑吾。志賀魯斯，松岡航平。入霧、鈴村由香。
MUTSUGI, TOMOKA KUROTANI. SHIRAHANE GODOU, MASATO OGIWARA.
MUTSUGI、黑谷智華。SHIRAHANE、荻原雅人。
Original work by KEITA AMEMIYA.
雨宮惠太的原創作品。
Executive producer, KIYOTAKA NINOMIYA.
執行製片人，二宮清隆。
Planning and producer, Tanaka Aya. Producer, Higa Ichiro, SHUHEI OKABAYASHI.
策劃兼製作人：Tanaka Aya。製作人：Higa Ichiro、岡林修平。
Photography by JUNYA HOSHI and AKIRA NISHIOKA.
攝影：JUNYA HOSHI 和 AKIRA NISHIOKA。
Stylist, MASAHIKO KURODA.
造型師黑田正彥。
Assistant director, JUNPEI SHIOKAWA, SHUHEI OKUMURA.
副導演鹽川純平、奧村週平。
Special cooperation, SANSEI R&D.
特別合作，三精研發。
Produced by TOHOKUSHINSHA.
東北新社製作。
Screenplay, RIUJI YOSHIZAKI. Screenplay cooperation: YASUHIRO MATSUDA.
劇本：吉崎理二。劇本合作：松田康紅。
Action director, MASAKI SUZUMURA.
動作導演鈴村正樹。
Director, YASUHIRO MATSUDA.
導演：松田康弘。
This story is a fiction. It has no relation to any real person, organization, or incident.
這個故事是虛構的。它與任何真實的人、組織或事件無關。
Did MUTSUGI move us intentionally?
MUTSUGI是故意感動我們的嗎？
Have you ever imagined a world without HORROR?
你曾經想像過一個沒有HORROR的世界嗎？
I can't let this gate open.
我不能讓這扇門打開。
gate.
門。